<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<descriptions>
    <java>
        Java is, by far, my favorite programming language. I am completely self taught in Java SE and EE. I have created
        multiple programs using both the Swing and JavaFX frameworks, and have used Java to create large scale web
        applications using JBoss Wildfly. I love creating open source software to benefit the community, because I
        believe large things can be achieved from small contributions. I am knowledgeable of many advanced Java concepts
        and frameworks, including Inheritance, EJBs, Servlets, JSF, and JPA. In my efforts to solve real-world problems
        with Java, I have teamed up to create a fully functional asset reservation system to replace outdated carbon
        copies in schools and businesses. I am selling the system through my company, AptiTekk, LLC.
    </java>
    <android>
        I have created multiple Android applications using Java and Android Studio. My most notable app, the "Bingham
        App", was created in a team for Bingham High School in South Jordan, Utah. This app used many advanced features,
        including overlaying the school map upon Google Maps. This allowed users to search for and find rooms easily,
        and see the rooms' locations in relation to the school parking lots.
    </android>
    <linux>
        This website and a couple of my other websites run on a Debian VPS (Virtual Private Server), installed and
        maintained by myself. I have an excellent knowledge of the commands, tools, and software necessary to manage a
        web server, and I am proficient in web server security. My server takes advantage of RSA keys and SSL
        certificates, and I use an installation of ISPConfig to manage my websites.
    </linux>
    <php>
        PHP is one of my favorite programming languages. I love creating secure and efficient server-sided code that
        serves a purpose. On an old website, I used PHP to create a rudimentary-yet-functional forum system, allowing
        users to register for an account and make threads and posts. It taught me a lot about implementing MySQL
        queries, avoiding SQL injections, and validating user input. I also learned to ensure that users’ private
        information, such as passwords and email addresses, were securely stored within the databases, and hashed where
        necessary.
    </php>
    <mysql>
        I have a strong grasp of MySQL queries, and am very confident in creating software and web applications that
        implement MySQL. I have used MySQL in quite a few projects in the past. MySQL is an integral part of an error
        report system built into many of my programs, allowing users to send logs and comments if the program crashes.
        All of my websites use MySQL, and are managed from the web via phpMyAdmin, and remotely via MySQL Workbench.
        Some of my software also includes support for SQLite, which is a great lightweight, file-based alternative to
        MySQL for small applications.
    </mysql>
    <wordpress>
        WordPress is consistently my #1 choice when deciding what framework to use when building websites. Most people
        see WordPress as something only used when creating blogs, but I find that it can be used for so much more; from
        blogs, to online marketplaces, to portfolios. In fact, this website runs on WordPress. I find comfort in using
        WordPress for many reasons, but mainly because of the ease-of-use and proven security. I have a lot of
        experience designing websites with WordPress, and I know how to make it do what I need it to do. I hope one day
        to create plugins for WordPress and give back to the amazing community.
    </wordpress>
    <autodesk>
        I love Autodesk products. Autodesk has many amazing tools that have assisted me in many ways. I am skilled in
        Inventor and Maya, and have a bit of experience working with 3ds Max.
        Using Inventor, I have created 3D visual models of most of my projects in woodshop at school, which gave me the
        chance to build and scale them exactly how I wanted them, then create drawings of the parts. This made the whole
        process of building my projects so much easier and faster, as I had the exact dimensions of every part and knew
        exactly how to assemble the projects. My favorite project was a hardwood porch swing I built from scratch.
        I have taken a half year class on Maya, and really enjoyed it. I am very capable of creating 3D models in Maya,
        and I know how to work with many different types of materials, including Phong, Blinn, and Mental Ray. I have
        created everything from small buildings to video game characters using Maya.
    </autodesk>
    <adobe>
        I use Adobe products constantly when designing websites and software. My two favorite tools are Photoshop and
        Illustrator, and I feel very confident and skilled while using them. I have experience using InDesign, Flash,
        Dreamweaver, Acrobat, and Bridge as well. I have studied the elements and principles of design, and I try to
        always create pleasing graphics, fine tuning them to perfection.
        I find Illustrator very useful in many different situations, not just in web design. For example, I have used
        Illustrator to design parts to be cut out of sheet metal and aluminum, which were used when building a truck at
        school. Illustrator is my go-to choice when designing logos, because I want to always retain the quality of the
        logo at any scale.
        I think Adobe products are invaluable and you can never go wrong with learning how to use them.
    </adobe>
</descriptions>